## SUDHIR KAUSHIK, MBA, PMP®

@: Kaushik.nt@hotmail.com Mobile: +86-1525-150-9001

**Nationality: Indian** 

#### **PROJECT MANAGEMENT • STRATEGY CONSULTANT • L&D SPECIALIST**



#### **SUMMARY AND SKILLS**

Sudhir **Kaushik** possesses 12-years' working experience with top MNCs and multicultural team. Kaushik is an avid learner and passionate towards following domains:

- Agile Methodologies
- Project Management
- Java Development

- Talent Development
- Business Communication
- Business Strategy

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Senior Consultant, Strategy Division, NTT DATA Corporation.

Wuxi, China

Dec 2013 ~ Now

- Agile Coaching.
- NTT DATA China's representative in APC (**Agile Professional Center**) Global Network.
- PMO's (Project Management Office) activities.
- Developing RFPs response and deliver proposal presentation (ENG Only).

Senior Trainer – IEB (International Education Business), NIIT Ltd.

Shanghai, China.

Oct 2007 ~ Dec 2013.

- Imparted IT training to undergraduate students in schools, colleges and universities in China.
- TOT (Training of Trainers) & Corporate Trainings.

Software Faculty → Academic Coordinator Titan & Softdot Technologies

New Delhi, India.

Apr 2004 ~ Oct 2007

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

1. My Website: www.vnvinfo.net

2. Project Name: Shanghai Sports Stadium (Jan 2015 till Dec 2015)

[Click Here] to view this application.

**Project Summary:** Shanghai sports stadium's customer management system. System had 3 interfaces – PC, mobile devices (Android and iOS). System serve the following users-

- **Customer** shall book, cancel or modify the various slots at multiple facilities to play badminton, table tennis, volleyball, basketball etc.
- Administrator shall manage all activities like sales promotion, ticket management.
- Field Manager shall manage the particular field related services.

#### My Roles & Responsibilities:

- Active participation in requirement analysis and design creation.
- Developing web interface.
- Project executive manage WBS, meetings and project communication.

**Technical Environment:** Java framework, Spring, JSP, HTML5, JQuery, MySQL, Apache Tomcat etc.

3. Manage and Supervise Numerous Academic Projects during my tenure in NIIT China as Senior IT Trainer.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

- MBA (International Business) from SM University India.
- MCA from IGNOU New Delhi India.
- M.Sc. (Statistics) from CCS University India.
- B.Sc. (Mathematics, Statistics, Physics) from CCS University India.
- 45 professional development courses from ELEMENT K, USA (Now SKILLSOFT).

**TECHNICAL SKILLS:** Java related skills (Core Java, Spring, Hibernate), MySQL, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery etc.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- PMI-PMP®
- SCJP
- MCPD (WINDOWS, WEB)
- NCC 'B' & 'C' Certificate

#### **AWARDS**

- Best Leader Award NCC Annual Camp.
- Best Speaker Award (Chinese) NTT DATA.
- Best Presentation Award (Chinese) NTT DATA.

**COMMUNITY SERVICE** Administer Weekly English Corner activities in Wuxi District Library. **BILINGUAL (CH-ENG) BLOG [Click Here]** 

LANGUAGE KNOWN: English, Chinese 中文, Hindi हिन्दी,

LINKED-IN PROFILE [Click Here]
ONLINE COPY OF RESUME [Click Here]

[Sudhir Kaushik]

# 高兴 KAUSHIK, MBA, PMP®

@: Kaushik.nt@hotmail.com Mobile: +86-1525-150-9001

国籍:印度

#### PROJECT MANAGEMENT • STRATEGY CONSULTANT • L&D SPECIALIST

#### 生涯概要:

高兴在 IT、业务培训、咨询以及项目管理方面拥有 12 年的学习发展经历。同时拥有以下领域的经验:

● 项目管理

● 敏捷方法论

● Java 开发

人才发展

● 商务沟通

● 商业战略

#### 经验:

高级顾问, 推进本部, NTT DATA 有限公司.

无锡,中国

2013.12~ 今日

- Agile Coaching.
- NTT DATA 中国的 APC(Agile Professional Center)负责代表
- PMO's (Project Management Office) activities.
- 撰写项目提案并负责提案的演讲(英语)

高级培训师-IEB (International Education Business), NIIT Ltd. 2007.10~2013.12.

上海,中国.

2007.10 2013.12.

- 给与应届毕业生 IT 培训
- 培训教师和企业培训

Software Faculty → Academic Coordinator Titan & Softdot Technologies

新德里,印度.

2004.04 ~ 2007.10

#### IT 项目经验

1. 我的网站: www.vnvinfo.net

2. 项目: 场馆售票管理系统 [Click Here] 看这个系统。(1月 2015 到 12月 2015)

客户:上海体育馆

项目概要:上海体育馆场馆售票管理系统拥有三个接口-PC端, Android和 iOS。系统有三种用户

- 用户可以注册,预定,取消,修改订单,比如:羽毛球,乒乓,篮球等等。
- 管理人可以管理所有的功能如:销售活动,票管理。
- 场馆可以管理各自场馆的服务.

### 我的角色与责任

- 参加需求分析和设计
- Project executive- 管理 WBS, 会议,项目沟通。

技术环境: Java 框架, Spring, JSP, HTML5, JQuery, MySQL, Apache Tomcat etc.

2. 管理和监督众多学术项目我的任期在 NIIT 中国高级 IT 培训期间。

#### 资格与培训

- MBA (International Business) from SM 大学, 印度.
- MCA from IGNOU 新德里, 印度.
- M.Sc. (统计学) from CCS 大学, 印度.
- **B.Sc.** (数学, 物理学, 统计学) from CCS 大学, 印度.
- 45 个专业发展课程 ELEMENT K, USA (现在是 Skillsoft).

技术技能: Java (Core Java, Spring, Hibernate), MySQL, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery etc.

#### IT 和专业证明书

- PMI-PMP®
- SCJP
- MCPD (WINDOWS, WEB)
- NCC 'B' & 'C' Certificate

#### 奖励

- 最佳领导奖 NCC
- 最佳演说奖 NTT DATA.
- 最佳表现奖 NTT DATA.

社区服务: 管理无锡区图书馆每周英语角活动。

写双语(中英)博客:[Click Here]

语言: 英语、中文、印度语

领英 PROFILE: [Click Here] 简历网上版: [Click Here]

[Sudhir Kaushik]